The Snowman is a adventure, animation, family film directed by Dianne Jackson.
A young boy makes a snowman one Christmas Eve, which comes to life at midnight and
takes him on a magical adventure to the North Pole to meet Santa Claus.
Older James / Narrator during original 1982 British television
broadcast (uncredited), played by Raymond Briggs.
Older James (re-released/US version), played by David Bowie.
Father Christmas - 20th Anniversary version, played by Mel Smith.
The Snowman is a 1982 British animated television film and symphonic poem
based on Raymond Briggs's 1978 picture book The Snowman.
It was directed by Dianne Jackson for Channel 4.
It was first shown on 26 December 1982, and was an immediate success.
It was nominated for Best Animated Short Film at the 55th
Academy Awards and won a BAFTA TV Award.
The story is told through pictures, action and music, scored by Howard Blake.
It has no dialogue, with the exception of the
central song, "Walking in the Air".
The orchestral score was performed by the Sinfonia of London and the song
was performed by Peter Auty, a St Paul's Cathedral choirboy.
The film ranked at number 71 on the 100 Greatest British Television Programmes, a list drawn up
by the British Film Institute in 2000, based on a vote by industry professionals.
It was voted number 4 in UKTV Gold's Greatest TV Christmas Moments.
It came third in Channel 4's poll of 100 Greatest Christmas Moments in 2004.
Its broadcast, usually on Christmas Eve on Channel 4, has become
an annual festive event in the UK and Ireland.
A sequel, The Snowman and the Snowdog, was released in 2012.
The film explores themes of holiday, little boy, snowman, christmas, short film.
The tone is lighthearted.